# SIMARPAL SINGH

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Software Engineer**

### Testingxperts (July 2021 to Current)

(TestingXperts is an independent software testing and DevOps company providing modern software services to global clients)

- I served as the Co-technical lead for an innovation project, spearheading the design of an AI/ML solution.
   Our goal was to identify and conduct impact analysis on unit test cases and regression test cases based on incremental commits. I effectively communicated our findings to stakeholders, advocating for the integration of our solution into the pipeline. This strategic move significantly reduced overall regression test execution time, enhancing efficiency and productivity.
- Worked as a MERN full-stack developer on a CMS for a South Africa based client.
  - Converted Figma design to reusable react components.
  - Built an express app to handle APIs and NoSql MongoDB to store and manage content and user data.
  - Deployed application on AWS with pm2 for managing express server and NGINX to bind redirect requests.
- Built a modern survey and maturity assessment Web portal, Using the following tech stack:-
  - Frontend-Typescript, react, and redux.
  - · Backend-Python, Django, and Postgres.
  - Managed and trained GETs and interns of the 2022 session.

### Intern Backend node.js Developer

PMIDC May 2021 to July 2021 (3 months)

(PMIDC is a State government Company with aim to uplift the living standard of the urban population in the State of Punjab)

- Worked on REST APIs for a Whatsapp Covid chatbot during the pandemic. (Our chatbot was featured in the national news channel)
- Assisted the project manager and worked alongside senior developers to prepare an implementation plan from a technical perspective.
- Cooperated with front-end developers and other team members to design more cohesive and functional code and tested software applications.



### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### B.E. (Bachelors in Engineering)

Computer Science Engineering with Hons. in Big Data Analytics, Chandigarh University (2017-2021)

Overall Score (7.01 CGPA)

- Actively participated in hackathons and extracurricular activities
- Cum Laude for the under-grad project (Crime Data Analysis)



🙂 +91 788873 - 9596

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous employee. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success. Seasoned Full-Stack experienced developing applications, databases and cloud computing solutions. Smart professional with proven troubleshooting and debugging capabilities for resolving complex technical issues.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

React.js | Node.js | Redux

Typescript | Javascript | Al

Express | MongoDB | Docker

Python | Git | HTML | CSS | AWS

### INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Team Leadership | Management

Coordination | Decision Making

Adaptability | Problem-solving

### LANGUAGE FLUENCY

English | Punjabi | Hindi

### PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

Exemplary delivery Award

Young Achiever Award & Certificate

### Academic Achievements Certification

- IBM Big Data Engineering Mastery Award
- IBM Big Data Engineering Explorer Award
- Machine learning and statistical inference By John Hopkins (Coursera)
- 6 months of industrial training in python